Inventory of the Donald S. Rothchild papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Research materials, 1975-1984
  - African unity and the O.A.U., 1967-1969 (Box-folder 92: 1)
  - African, Caribbean and Pacific countries, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 92: 2)
  - Northern Ireland, 1969-1995 (Box-folder 93: 1-4)
  - Iraqi Kurdistan, 1994-2002 (Box-folder 93: 5)
  - East Timor/Indonesia, 1999 (Box-folder 93: 6)
  - Organization of African Unity, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 93: 7)
  - Egypt: Copts, 1973 (Box-folder 94: 1)
  - Algeria, 1958-2003 (Box-folder 94: 2)
  - Fiji, 1986-2000 (Box-folder 94: 3)
  - El Salvador, 1997 (Box-folder 94: 4)
  - Ethiopian/Eritrean war, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 94: 5)
  - Guatemala, 1997 (Box-folder 94: 6)
  - Guinea: ethnic management, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 94: 7)
  - India: federalism, 1960-1987 (Box-folder 94: 8)
  - Cameroon: unification, 1965-1992 (Box-folder 95: 1)
  - Cameroon: general, 1991-2002 (Box-folder 95: 2)
  - Canada, 1966-1991 (Box-folder 95: 3)
  - Burkina Fao/Touareg negotiations, 1994 (Box-folder 95: 4)
  - Armenia: genocide, 1973-1995 (Box-folder 95: 5)
  - Algeria, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 95: 6)
  - Barotseland, 1968 (Box-folder 95: 7)
  - Bangladesh, 1972 (Box-folder 95: 8)
  - Cyprus, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 95: 9)
  - African peacekeeping, 2000 (Box-folder 96: 1)
  - Cyprus, 1974-1992 (Box-folder 96: 2)
  - Casamance, 2001 (Box-folder 96: 3)
  - Central African Republic, 2001 (Box-folder 96: 4)
  - China, 1966-1993 (Box-folder 96: 5)
  - Confederation, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 96: 6)
  - Congo-Brazzaville, 1997 (Box-folder 96: 7)
  - Oil and federalism, 1967 (Box-folder 96: 8)
  - Chiapas, 1990-2001 (Box-folder 96: 9)
  - Pan-Africanism, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 96: 10)
  - Benin, 1971-1996 (Box-folder 96: 11)
  - Belgium, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 96: 12)
  - Nigeria, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 97: 1)
  - Babawgida regime, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 97: 2-3)
  - Buhari regime, 1984 (Box-folder 97: 4)
  - Nigeria: elections, 1983 (Box-folder 97: 5)
  - Soviet and American policy toward Southern Africa, 1988 (Box-folder 98: 1)
  - Soviet Union, 1967-1995 (Box-folder 98: 2)
  - Spain, 1975-2006 (Box-folder 98: 3)
  - East Timor and the U.S., 1975 (Box-folder 98: 4)
  - Togo, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 98: 5)
  - Yugoslav regionalism, 1955-1988 (Box-folder 98: 6)
  - Zambia, 1974-1987 (Box-folder 98: 7)
  - Zanzibar, 1969 (Box-folder 98: 8)
  - Zaire: ethnic management, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 98: 9)
  - Zimbabwe, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 98: 10)
  - Senegal, 1991-2005 (Box-folder 99: 1-2)
  - U.S. tilt toward Pakistan, 2002 (Box-folder 99: 3)
  - East Pakistan-Bangladesh, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 99: 4)
  - Sierra Leone, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 99: 5-7)
  - American-Soviet symposiums on Africa, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 99: 8-9)
  - Nigeria, 1982-2006 (Box-folder 100: 1-4)
  - West Pakistan/East Pakistan, 1971-1988 (Box-folder 100: 5-6)
  - Ottoman Empire, 1974 (Box-folder 100: 7)
  - Scottish nationalism and U.K. federalism, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 100: 8)
  - Ivory Coast, 1982-2006 (Box-folder 101: 1-12)
  - Western Sahara, 1976-1991 (Box-folder 102: 1-5)
  - Ivory Coast, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 102: 6-7)
  - Nigeria/Biafra, 1990 (Box-folder 103: 1)
  - Congo, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 103: 2-6)
  - Rhodesia: Australian influence, 1981 (Box-folder 103: 8)
  - Stedman: Kissinger and Geneva conference, 1990 (Box-folder 103: 9)
  - Zimbabwe, 1979 (Box-folder 103: 10)
  - Western Sahara, 1990-2002 (Box-folder 103: 11-12)
  - Lancaster House proceedings, 1979 (Box-folder 104: 1-3)
  - Rhodesia, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 104: 4)
  - Congo, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 104: 5-11)
  - Rwanda-Congo accord, 2002 (Box-folder 104: 12)
  - Bosnia, 1994 (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - Cyrus Vance memoir, 1992 (Box-folder 105: 2)
  - Zimbabwe, 1979 (Box-folder 105: 3)
  - Lessons from Rhodesia, 1987 (Box-folder 105: 4)
  - Namibia and Zimbabwe, 1982 (Box-folder 105: 5)
  - Rhodesian negoatiations, 1981 (Box-folder 105: 6)
  - Conflict resolution in Southern Africa, 1982 (Box-folder 105: 7)
  - Rhodesia settlement, 1981 (Box-folder 105: 8)
  - Rhodesia: negotiations, 1979 (Box-folder 105: 9)
  - Zimbabwe negotiations: Malta, 1987 (Box-folder 105: 10)
  - Zimbabwe: report on constitutional conference, 1979 (Box-folder 105: 11)
  - Rhodesia, 1972 (Box-folder 105: 12)
  - Lancaster House proceedings, 1979 (Box-folder 105: 13)
  - Zimbabwe: British parliamentary debates, 1979 (Box-folder 105: 14)
  - Johnson administration: Zimbabwe, 1966 (Box-folder 105: 15)
  - Yugoslav separatism and U.S. policy, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 106: 1)
  - Bosnia, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 106: 2)
  - U.S. Immigration policy, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 106: 3)
  - Northern Ireland, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 106: 4)
  - Ulster agreement, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 106: 5)
  - U.S. and Northern Ireland, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 106: 6)
  - U.S. and Kurdish rebellion, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 106: 7)
  - U.S. and Kurdish self-determination, 1948-1991 (Box-folder 106: 8)
  - U.S. and self-determination, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 106: 9)
  - Bosnia, 1994 (Box-folder 106: 10)
  - China/Tibet, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 107: 1)
  - Tibetan protest and U.S. involvement, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 107: 2)
  - U.S. and Quebec separatism, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 107: 3)
  - U.S. cultural pluralism versus assimilation, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 107: 4)
  - U.S. trade-Soviet emigration, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 107: 5)
  - Detente versus human rights, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 107: 6)
  - U.S. mediation-Central America, 1990 (Box-folder 107: 7)
  - Self-deetermination, 1980 (Box-folder 107: 8)
  - International politics and race relations, 1972-1989 (Box-folder 107: 9)
  - U.S. bilingualism, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 107: 10)
  - U.S. and Puerto Rico, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 107: 11)
  - India: U.S. support for unity, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 107: 12)
  - U.S. and Yugoslav separatism, 1991 (Box-folder 107: 13)
  - Kissinger policy: Pakistan, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 107: 14)
  - U.S. and Idi Amin, 1972-1986 (Box-folder 108: 1)
  - U.S. and Fiji-alleged intervention, 1987 (Box-folder 108: 2)
  - U.S. and self-determinatoin, 1967-1994 (Box-folder 108: 3-4)
  - John F. Kennedy and Algerian self-determination, 1957-1988 (Box-folder 108: 5)
  - Woodrow Wilson and self-determination, 1974 (Box-folder 108: 6)
  - U.S. and Armenian mandate, 1985 (Box-folder 108: 7)
  - U.S. and rights of Falashas, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 108: 8)
  - U.S. and Guyana: intervention, 1983 (Box-folder 108: 9)
  - Communal conflict and international intervention in Africa, 1979 (Box-folder 108: 10)
  - Ethnic factor in world politics, 1975 (Box-folder 108: 11)
  - Ethnicity and external intervention, 1985 (Box-folder 108: 12)
  - U.S. and Israel, 1988-2001 (Box-folder 108: 13)
  - U.S. globalist perceptions, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 108: 14)
  - Soviet nationalities-U.S. policy, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 109: 1)
  - Cyprus, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 109: 2)
  - Nigeria, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 109: 3-5)
  - Pan-Africanism versus Portugal in Africa, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 109: 6)
  - U.S. and nationalities problem, 1985-1999 (Box-folder 110: 1-2)
  - Reluctant enforcer: U.S. and ethnic conflict, 1999 (Box-folder 110: 3)
  - Liberal society and the Indian question, 1970 (Box-folder 110: 4)
  - Stages of mediation, 1989 (Box-folder 110: 5)
  - Africa's ethnic conflicts, 1988 (Box-folder 110: 6)
  - Sri Lanka-U.S. pressure, 1990 (Box-folder 110: 7)
  - U.S. aid as pressure, 1983 (Box-folder 110: 9)
  - Democracy, U.S. foreign policy, and that nationalities question, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 110: 11)
  - American political culture, 1985 (Box-folder 110: 12)
  - Non-interventionist policy, 1986 (Box-folder 110: 13)
  - Humanitarian intervention, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 110: 14)
  - U.S. reluctance to mediate, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 110: 15)
  - U.S. and nationalities problem, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 110: 16)
- Printed matter, 1955-1980
  - Nigeria, 1955-1970
    - 1955 (Box-folder 111: 1)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 111: 2)
    - 1959 (Box-folder 111: 3-5)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 111: 6)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 111: 7)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 111: 8)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 111: 9)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 111: 10)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 111: 11-12)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 111: 13-14)
  - Ghana, 1964-1984
    - 1964 (Box-folder 112: 1)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 112: 2)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 112: 3)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 112: 4)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 112: 5)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 112: 6-7)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 112: 8-11)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 112: 12-14)
  - West Africa, 1982
    - 1982 (Box-folder 112: 15)
  - West Africa, 1967
    - 1967 (Box-folder 113: 1)
  - Nigeria, 1963-1975
    - 1963 (Box-folder 113: 2)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 113: 3-4)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 113: 5)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 113: 6)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 113: 7-11)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 113: 12)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 113: 13)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 113: 14)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 113: 15-26)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 113: 17)
  - Ghana, 1978-1986
    - 1978 (Box-folder 114: 1)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 114: 2)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 114: 3)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 114: 4)
  - Nigeria, 1958-1976
    - 1958 (Box-folder 114: 5-8)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 114: 9)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 114: 10-11)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 114: 12)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 114: 13)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 114: 14-20)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 114: 21)
  - Ghana, 1983
    - 1983 (Box-folder 115: 1-3)
- Research materials, 1946-2000
  - Ethiopia, 1946-1962 (Box-folder 115: 4-7)
  - Ethiopia and Angola, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 116: 1)
  - Ethiopian negotiations, 1991 (Box-folder 116: 2)
  - Ethiopian constitution, 1994 (Box-folder 116: 3)
  - Soviet involvement in Ethiopia, 1969 (Box-folder 116: 4)
  - U.S. mediation in Ethiopia, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 116: 5)
  - Ethiopia, 1980-1994 (Box-folder 116: 6-7)
  - Ethiopian-Eritrean conflict, 2000 (Box-folder 116: 8)
  - Ethiopia-Somali agreement, 1988 (Box-folder 117: 1)
  - Ethiopia ethnicity, 1977-1988 (Box-folder 117: 2)
  - Eritrea, 1949-1996 (Box-folder 117: 3)
  - Ethiopia/Eritrea, 1949-1989 (Box-folder 117: 4-5)
  - U.S. and Eritrea, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 117: 6)
  - U.S. and Ethiopian nationalities, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 117: 7)
  - Addis Ababa agreement, 1972 (Box-folder 117: 8)
  - Somali territorial claims, 1976 (Box-folder 117: 9)
  - Ethiopia/Somalia, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 117: 11)
  - Miscellaneous Africa, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 117: 12)
  - Ethiopia, 1974-1994 (Box-folder 118: 1-2)
  - Eritrea/Ethiopia, 1955-1989 (Box-folder 118: 3-4)
  - Eritrea, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 118: 5)
  - United Nations documents on Eritrea, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 118: 6)
  - Ethiopian/Eritrean panel, 2000 (Box-folder 119: 1)
  - Ethiopia/Eritrea, 1987-2003 (Box-folder 119: 2-6)
  - Ethiopia, 2001 (Box-folder 119: 7)
  - Partition, 1963-2003 (Box-folder 120: 1)
  - Guatemala, 1985-1998 (Box-folder 120: 2)
  - Political coalition: Guinea, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 120: 3)
  - Political coalition: Frelimo/Renamo, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 120: 4)
  - Western Sahara, 1990-2006 (Box-folder 120: 5-8)
  - Polisario, 2003 (Box-folder 120: 9)
  - Power-sharing-Malaysia, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 121: 1)
  - Federalism and minorities, 1962-1984 (Box-folder 121: 2)
  - Power-sharing-Afghanistan/Iraq, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 121: 3)
  - Political coaltion: Northern Ireland, 1974-2001 (Box-folder 121: 4)
  - Peacebuilding and the lilmits of liberal internationalism, 1997 (Box-folder 121: 5)
  - Partition, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 121: 6-7)
  - Autonomy, 1966-1998 (Box-folder 122: 1)
  - Namibia: Kissinger period, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 122: 2)
  - Namibia: McHenry period, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 122: 3)
  - Namibia: Africa conference, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 122: 4)
  - Zoning: Nigerian parties, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 122: 5)
  - Namibian negotiations: overview, 1966-1991 (Box-folder 122: 6)
  - Namibia-Gerald Ford Library, 1976 (Box-folder 122: 7)
  - Pacted democracy, 1986-1994 (Box-folder 122: 8)
  - Canadian federalism, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 123: 1)
  - Sudanese federalism, 1997 (Box-folder 123: 2)
  - Federalism: Cameroon, 1995 (Box-folder 123: 3)
  - Swiss federalism, 1998 (Box-folder 123: 4)
  - Pakistan: federalism, 1998 (Box-folder 123: 5)
  - Confederalism, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 123: 6)
  - Federalism/autonomy definitions, 1998 (Box-folder 123: 7)
  - Namibia, 1978-2000 (Box-folder 123: 8-10)
  - Namibia: Crocker period, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 123: 11)
  - Power-sharing-Haiti, 2000 (Box-folder 123: 12)
  - Proportional representation and minorities, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 123: 13)
  - Sierra Leone: peace agreement, 2001 (Box-folder 123: 14)
  - Burundi, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 123: 15)
  - Rwanda, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 124: 1-3)
  - Philippines accord, 1976-2000 (Box-folder 124: 4)
  - Bosnian autonomy, 1998 (Box-folder 124: 5)
  - Russian federalism, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 124: 6)
  - Ethiopian federalism, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 124: 7)
  - Alan Kuperman: Rwanda, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 125: 1)
  - Rwanda, 1990-2002 (Box-folder 125: 2-4)
  - Rwanda-Security Council inquiry, 1999 (Box-folder 125: 5)
  - Rwanda-National Security Archive, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 125: 6)
  - Great Lakes region in Africa, 2003 (Box-folder 125: 7)
  - U.S. and African development, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 126: 1)
  - U.S. foreign policy-institutional structure, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 126: 2)
  - Burundi: end of transition, 2004 (Box-folder 126: 3)
  - Burundi: Truth Commission, 2004 (Box-folder 126: 4)
  - Burundi: genocide, 1972-2004 (Box-folder 126: 5)
  - Burundi, 1994-2005 (Box-folder 126: 6-8)
  - Burundi: International Crisis Group report, 2003 (Box-folder 126: 9)
  - Rwanda, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 126: 10)
  - French report on Rwanda, 2000 (Box-folder 126: 11)
  - U.S. and Rwanda: inaction, 1994-2005 (Box-folder 126: 12)
  - U.S. and Africa, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 127: 1-2)
  - U.S. and West Africa, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 127: 3)
  - Afro-Marxist regimes, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 127: 4)
  - U.S.-Soviet relations concerning Africa, 1978-1988 (Box-folder 127: 5)
  - Reagan: foreign assistance, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 127: 6)
  - U.S. and Ethiopia, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 127: 7)
  - U.S. and Africa, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 128: 1-2)
  - Reagan and Africa, 1981 (Box-folder 128: 3)
  - Reaganomics and Africa, 1981 (Box-folder 128: 4)
  - U.S. interest groups and Africa, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 128: 5)
  - Regionalism/globalism, 1981 (Box-folder 128: 6)
  - American policy on Africa, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 128: 7)
  - African criticisms of Reagan, 1981 (Box-folder 128: 8)
  - Burundi, 1975-1989 (Box-folder 129: 1-3)
  - Africa and democracy, 1959-1991 (Box-folder 129: 4-6)
  - Reagan and Africa, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 129: 7-8)
  - Polyarchy: Senegal, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 130: 1)
  - Political coalition, 1969-1987 (Box-folder 130: 2)
  - Implications of regime performance, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 130: 3)
  - U.S. and Cyprus negotiations, 1974-1998 (Box-folder 130: 4)
  - Cyprus: 1960 constitution (Box-folder 130: 5)
  - Cyprus: Johnson administration, 1964 (Box-folder 130: 5)
  - Cyprus, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 130: 6)
  - Democracy, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 130: 7)
  - Demand for democracy, 1996 (Box-folder 130: 8)
  - Western Sahara, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 131: 1-4)
  - Lebanon (1958)-Whitman papers (Box-folder 131: 5-6)
  - Ethiopia, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 131: 7-8)
  - Civil society, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 132: 1-2)
  - Cyprus, 1959-2002 (Box-folder 132: 3-7)
  - Political coalition: Kenya, 1974-1988 (Box-folder 132: 8)
  - Sudan, 2004 (Box-folder 133: 1)
  - National conference phenomenon in Francophone Africa, 1994 (Box-folder 133: 2)
  - House of Chiefs: Indigenizing Democracy in Africa?, 2002 (Box-folder 133: 3)
  - Polyarchy, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 133: 4)
  - Regimes, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 133: 5)
  - Democracy, 1959-2002 (Box-folder 133: 6)
  - Articles and papers on the state, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 133: 7)
  - Hegemony and ethnicity, 1960-1988 (Box-folder 134: 1)
  - Hegemonial exchange, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 134: 2)
  - Coalition formation: Cameroon, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 134: 3)
- Printed matter, 1962-2002
  - Africa, 2002
    - 2002 (Box-folder 134: 4-5)
  - East Africa, 1969
    - 1969 (Box-folder 134: 6)
  - Kenya, 1966-1977
    - 1966 (Box-folder 134: 7-12)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 134: 13)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 134: 14)
  - Uganda, 1962
    - 1962 (Box-folder 134: 15)
  - Nigeria, 1958-1983
    - 1958 (Box-folder 135: 1)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 135: 2-6)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 135: 7-8)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 135: 9-10)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 135: 11-12)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 135: 13)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 135: 14)
  - Africa, 1971
    - 1971 (Box-folder 135: 15)
  - East Africa, 1970
    - 1970 (Box-folder 135: 16)
  - Uganda, 1978
    - 1978 (Box-folder 135: 17)
  - Kenya, 1973-1992
    - 1973 (Box-folder 135: 18)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 135: 19)
  - Ghana, 1980-1993
    - 1980 (Box-folder 135: 20)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 135: 21-23)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 135: 24-25)
  - Nigeria, 1966-1969
    - 1966 (Box-folder 135: 26-27)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 135: 28)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 135: 29)
- Research materials, 1958-1980
  - Kenyatta succession, 1979 (Box-folder 136: 1)
  - Limann, Hella, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 136: 2)
  - Separate states: Nigeria, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 136: 3)
  - Nigeria: minorities and new states, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 136: 4)
  - Uganda new districts: Sebei-Bamba Bakanjo, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 136: 5)
  - Nigeria: 1992 election (Box-folder 136: 6)
  - Biafran War: Tanzania and Ivory Coast, 1968 (Box-folder 137: 1)
  - Ghana, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 137: 2)
  - Zimbabwe unity accord, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 137: 3)
  - Provincialization, 1983 (Box-folder 137: 4)
  - Ghana: decentralization, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 137: 5)
  - Decentralization, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 137: 6)
  - Barotseland, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 137: 7)
- Printed matter, 1966-1993
  - Africa, 1967-1990
    - 1967 (Box-folder 137: 8)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 137: 9)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 137: 10-11)
  - Ghana, 1991-1993
    - 1991 (Box-folder 137: 12-13)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 137: 14)
  - Nigeria, 1967-1987
    - 1967 (Box-folder 137: 15-16)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 137: 17-20)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 137: 21)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 137: 22)
  - Uganda, 1966-1993
    - 1966 (Box-folder 137: 23)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 137: 24)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 137: 25)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 137: 26)
- Research materials, 1970-1980
  - Lancaster House proceedings, 1979 (Box-folder 138: 1-2)
  - Zimbabwe: mediation and U.S. polilcy, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 138: 3)
  - Zimbabwe: negotiations, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 138: 4-5)
  - Rhodesia Zimbabwe African conference, 1979 (Box-folder 138: 6)
  - Rhodesia, 1965-1980 (Box-folder 138: 7-9)
  - Zimbabwe, 1980-2005 (Box-folder 139: 1-3)
  - U.S. and Zimbabwe, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 139: 4)
  - Zimbabwe: coalition, 1972-1995 (Box-folder 139: 5)
  - Zimbabwe: International Crisis Group reports, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 139: 6-7)
  - Unilateral Declaration of Independence in Rhodesia, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 139: 8)
  - Zimbabwe: Constitution, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 139: 9)
  - Sanctions and the Rhodesian economy, 1969 (Box-folder 139: 10)
  - U.S. and Africa: Kissinger, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 139: 11)
  - Racial reconciliation in Southern Africa, 1989 (Box-folder 140: 1)
  - From Rhodesia to Zimbabwe, 1985 (Box-folder 140: 2)
  - Brzezinski on Zimbabwe, 1985 (Box-folder 140: 3)
  - Zimbabwe's lessons, 1987 (Box-folder 140: 4)
  - Peacemaking in a revolutionary civil war, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 5)
  - Carter policy: Rhodesia, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 140: 6)
  - Schutz: Rhodesia, 1968 (Box-folder 140: 7)
  - The war against Zimbabwe, 1979 (Box-folder 140: 8)
  - Zimbabwe: A status report, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 9)
  - Zimbabwe election 1980, 1981 (Box-folder 140: 10)
  - Zimbabwe negotiations, 1984 (Box-folder 140: 11)
  - Thatcher on Rhodesia, 1985 (Box-folder 140: 12)
  - Zimbabwe, 2003 (Box-folder 140: 13)
  - Zimbabawe: International Crisis Group reports, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 140: 14)
  - Zimbabwe: Mondale/Vorster meeting, 1977 (Box-folder 140: 15)
  - Miscellaneous Rhodesia/Zimbabwe, 1972-1985 (Box-folder 140: 16)
  - Rhodesia and Nyasaland, 1960-1979 (Box-folder 141: 1)
  - Federation in Rhodesia and Nyasaland, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 141: 2)
  - Zimbabwe, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 141: 3-5)
  - Zimbabwe settlement, 1985 (Box-folder 141: 6)
  - Kissinger and Rhodesia, 1980 (Box-folder 141: 7)
  - Zimbabwe: 1979 Commonwealth conference, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 141: 8)
  - Southern Africa: The year of the whirlwind, 1980 (Box-folder 141: 9)
  - Zimbabwe independence: National Security Archive, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 141: 10)
  - Federal military government views, 1976 (Box-folder 142: 1)
  - Federation in Rhodesia and Nyasaland, 1952-1960 (Box-folder 142: 2-3)
- Printed matter, 1958-1980
  - East Africa, 1968
    - 1968 (Box-folder 142: 4)
  - Ghana, 1969
    - 1969 (Box-folder 142: 5)
  - Kenya
    - 1966 (Box-folder 142: 6)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 142: 7)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 142: 8)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 142: 9)
  - Ghana, 1969-1979
    - 1969 (Box-folder 143: 1)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 143: 2-3)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 143: 4)
  - Uganda, 1963-1967
    - 1963 (Box-folder 143: 5)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 143: 6)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 143: 7-8)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 143: 9)
  - Africa, 1968
    - 1968 (Box-folder 144: 1)
  - Ghana, 1965-1976
    - 1965 (Box-folder 144: 2)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 144: 3-4)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 144: 5)
  - Uganda, 1961-1967
    - 1961 (Box-folder 144: 6)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 144: 7-9)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 144: 10)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 144: 11)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 144: 12)
  - Africa, 1967-1972
    - 1967 (Box-folder 145: 1)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 145: 2)
  - Uganda, 1962-1966
    - 1962 (Box-folder 145: 3)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 145: 4)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 145: 5-6)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 145: 7-12)
  - Africa, 1967
    - 1967 (Box-folder 146: 1)
  - Kenya, 1970
    - 1970 (Box-folder 146: 2)
  - Uganda, 1966-1969
    - 1966 (Box-folder 146: 3)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 146: 4)
- Research materials, 1958-1972
  - Uganda, 1972 (Box-folder 146: 5)
  - South Africa, 1954-1966 (Box-folder 146: 6-7)
  - Nyasaland, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 146: 8)
  - Political power: unilateral declaration of independence, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 146: 9)
  - Federalism: Uganda, 1959-1994 (Box-folder 146: 10)
  - Federalism: South Africa, 1960-1973 (Box-folder 146: 11)
- Printed matter, 1950-1978
  - Africa, 1954-1969
    - 1954 (Box-folder 147: 1)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 147: 2)
  - Zambia, 1971
    - 1971 (Box-folder 147: 3)
  - Uganda, 1971-1973
    - 1971 (Box-folder 147: 4)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 147: 5)
  - Nigeria, 1950-1960
    - 1950 (Box-folder 147: 6)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 147: 7)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 147: 8)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 147: 9-12)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 147: 13-14)
  - Kenya, 1955-1992
    - 1955 (Box-folder 147: 15)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 147: 16)
    - 1964-1967 (Box-folder 147: 17)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 147: 18)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 147: 19-20)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 147: 21-22)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 147: 23-24)
- Research materials, 1923-1983
  - External pressures, 1961-1977 (Box-folder 148: 1)
  - Fundamental rights, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 148: 2)
  - Franchise, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 148: 3)
  - Zambia: ethnic relations, 1968-1980 (Box-folder 148: 4-5)
  - Kenyan Indian Congress, 1923-1971 (Box-folder 148: 6)
  - Kenyan Indian Congress, 1923-1971 (Box-folder 149: 1)
  - Tanzanian Asians, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 149: 2)
  - Status of Asians: Uganda, 1961-1973 (Box-folder 149: 3)
  - Southern Rhodesia, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 149: 4)
  - Zambia: racial situation, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 149: 5-6)
  - Zanzibar, 1936-1963 (Box-folder 150: 1)
  - Expatriates in Africa, 1967-1981 (Box-folder 150: 2)
  - Zambia: race relations, 1971-1992 (Box-folder 150: 3)
  - South Africa, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 150: 4-5)